<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sammy Chen&#39;s Blogs on Portfolio website for Sammy C Chen</title>
    <link>/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sammy Chen&#39;s Blogs on Portfolio website for Sammy C Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:27:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Appropriation-Suicide/homicide rates between races</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog5/</guid>
      <description>It is unknown how much the difference in excess deaths due to homicide among black men and suicide among white men vary by US state.
To compare the rates of firearm and non-firearm homicide and suicide in black and white non-Hispanic men by US state and examine their associations with state prevalence of gun ownership.
In analysis part, I not only pointed out the circumstances but also bring out the resolutions in the concept of “cultural appropriation”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP component and proportion comparison</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog6/</guid>
      <description>GDP components over time and among countriesAt the risk of oversimplifying things, the main components of gross domestic product, GDP are personal consumption (C), business investment (I), government spending (G) and net exports (exports - imports). You can read more about GDP and the different approaches in calculating at the Wikipedia GDP page.
#read the dataset UN_GDP_data &amp;lt;- read_excel(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Download-GDPconstant-USD-countries.xls&amp;quot;), # Excel filenamesheet=&amp;quot;Download-GDPconstant-USD-countr&amp;quot;, # Sheet nameskip=2) # Number of rows to skipThe first thing is to tidy the data, as it is in wide format and you must make it into long, tidy format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump approval rate changes</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog7/</guid>
      <description>By looking at Trump’s Approval Margins over time, we can probably figure out the pattern of his approval rate change.
Let’s see from the past and dig as much deeper as we can!
First, we import the data set. We can also read csv directly from the website. Here we save the csv to local directory for higher speed.
# Import approval polls dataapproval_polllist &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;#39;data&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;approval_polllist.csv&amp;#39;))# or directly off fivethirtyeight website# approval_polllist &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;#39;https://projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sammy Chen</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Made in China. Sammy Chen enjoys city pop music, food and tennis. Have an everlasting love for Eastern literature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>